<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<encyclopedia xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:id="WP">
	<article xml:id="WP-01">
       <dc:title>Patrizia Cavalli</dc:title>
       <dc:creator>Sara Coppini</dc:creator>
       <dc:date>2019-06-08</dc:date>
       <dc:subject>poetry</dc:subject>
       <dc:subject>women</dc:subject>
       <dc:description>Patrizia Cavalli was born in Todi, Italy, the 17th of April, 1947. She left her hometown for Rome, in order to study Philosophy at La Sapienza University.The capital has been, for her, a place of important meetings and self-assertion as a poet, thanks also to the close relationship with Elsa Morante. She did various jobs in life but she has never abandoned poetry, from the age of twenty, when she gave a small booklet of thirty poems to Morante. She has published some successful collections for Einaudi's Poetry Section: My poems will not change the world (1974), Il cielo (1981), Poesie 1974-1992 (1992), L'io singolare proprio mio (1992) and Sempre teatro aperto (1999 Literary Prize Viareggio-Repaci), Pigre divinità e pigra sorte (2006 Dessì Prize). The last collection is Datura (2013). Still for the publisher Einaudi she translated Anfitrione di Molière and Shakespeare's A Midsummer Night's Dream, and also Otello, staged by the director and actor Arturo Cirillo in 2009. She has collaborated with many artists in the music industry, as a song writer for instance. Cavalli's poetry is characterized by a complex poetic technique. The metric measures used are classic, but the lexicon and syntax are those of the contemporary language; poeticisms and mannerisms are absent, and the language is everyday and familiar. </dc:description>
       <dc:publisher>Alma Mater Studiorum - Università di Bologna</dc:publisher>
       <dc:type>encyclopedic article</dc:type>
       <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
       <dc:coverage>Bologna</dc:coverage>
       <dc:rights>Copyright 2019 Sara Coppini</dc:rights>
    </article>
</encyclopedia>